Winter Study Records UA221
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Winter Study Records
1968 -- 1974
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
School of Engineering
School of Arts and Sciences
UA221
0.5 Linear Feet 1 box
This collection contains records from 1968-1974 regarding the experimental short-term academic and internship program called "Winter Study."
Arrangement
This collection is organized into two series: Program administration; and Winter Study publications.
Custodial History
Initially part of unprocessed collection UA058, box 15, it was separated out into its own collection in June, 2011. The publication series, Winter Study, was associated with the administrative records producing it. Series 2, Publications, was found in the basement of Ballou Hall on Tufts Campus in Summer 2010.
Scope and Contents
This collection is composed of administrative notes, survey results, student writings, photographs, and publications from 1968-1974 regarding the experimental short-term academic and internship program called "Winter Study." First run in January, 1969, the program was called "January Experiment," then interchangeably referred to as "January Thing" or "Jan Plan," and finally called "Winter Study" from 1971-1974.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research.
Curriculum and Instruction; Curriculum and Instruction -- Student Work
- Program Administration, 1968 -- 1974; UA221.001; 0.25 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains administrative notes, survey results, suggested course and internship descriptions, student writings resulting from the program, and photographs of winter study courses from 1968-1974 produced by Winter Study Committee.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Winter Study [1], 1968 -- 1970; UA221.001.001.00001 (Box UA221 Shared 1)
  - Winter Study [2], 1971; UA221.001.001.00002 (Box UA221 Shared 1)
  - Winter Study [3], 1972 -- 1973; UA221.001.001.00003 (Box UA221 Shared 1)
  - Winter Study [4], 1973 -- 1974; UA221.001.001.00004 (Box UA221 Shared 1)
  - January Thing photos, 1970; UA221.001.001.00005 (Box UA221 Shared 1)
- Winter Study Publications, 1969 -- 1974; 1971 -- 1974; UA221.002; 0.25 Linear Feet
  This series contains the publication from 1971-1974 listing student courses and internship for Winter Study period.
  - January Bulletin, 1969; UA221.002.001.00006 (Box UA221 Shared 1)
    Materials were photocopied from originals due to mold growth.
  - Guide to Winter Study, 1971; UA221.002.001.00007 (Box UA221 Shared 1)
  - Guide to Winter Study, 1972; UA221.002.001.00008 (Box UA221 Shared 1)
  - Guide to Winter Study, 1973; UA221.002.001.00009 (Box UA221 Shared 1)
  - Guide to Winter Study, 1974; UA221.002.001.00010 (Box UA221 Shared 1)